Guide to the Arthur Frederick and Mary Clabaugh Wright Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Arthur Frederick and Mary Clabaugh Wright papers
1928-1982
1951-1977
MS 876
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
28.75
(53 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, notes, manuscripts, and subject files from Arthur Frederick Wright's teaching career at Stanford University and at Yale University, his research on Chinese history, and his work for the Association for Asian Studies and the American Council of Learned Societies' Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization. The papers also include personal correspondence of the Wright and Clabaugh families. There is minimal material documenting Mary Clabaugh Wright's career.
Wright, Arthur F., 1913-1976
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Arthur F. Wright, 1978-1981; Jonathan A. Wright, 1981; and John King Fairbank, 1982. Transfer from East Asian Collection, 2000. Gift of Charles Duncan Wright and Jonathan Arthur Wright, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
ARTHUR FREDERICK WRIGHT, 1913-1976
Arthur Frederick Wright was born in Portland, Oregon, on December 3, 1913, the son of Charles Frederick and Georgiana Gwynne Wright. After graduating from Stanford University in 1935, Wright earned at B. Litt from the University of Oxford in 1937. He returned to the United States and began his graduate studies in Chinese and Japanese at Harvard University. While at Harvard he met Mary Oliver Clabaugh, another student of Chinese history. They were married on July 6, 1940, in the same year that Wright received his A.M.
After their wedding, the Wrights left the United States to study in Japan and China. When Japan attacked the United States on December 7, 1941, the Wrights were trapped in Peking. They continued to live on their own until March 24, 1943, when they, along with Peking's other enemy aliens, were arrested by Japanese authorities and sent to a prison camp at Wei-hsien, Shantung, until the end of the war. During this period Arthur wright worked as a butcher, water-carrier, and fireman.
After the war, the Wrights remained in China for further study and travel. In 1947 Arthur Wright received his Ph.D. from Harvard and joined the faculty of Stanford University, where he remained through 1959. In 1959, Wright was appointed a full professor at Yale University and in 1961 he was named the first Charles Seymour professor of history, a position he held until his death.
Wright's original field of research was the history of Buddhism and the relationship between Buddhism and politics. These studies appeared in 1958 in Buddhism in Chinese History. He was also an editor and contributor to Studies in Chinese Thought, Confucianism in Action, The Confucian Persuasion, Confucian Personalities, and Confucianism and Chinese Civilization. In later work Wright studied the T'ang dynasty, particularly its capital city Chiang-an, which led to his interest in urbanization. He also produced a lengthy chapter on the Sui for the Cambridge History of China and had an ongoing interest in Chinese historiography.
Wright was particularly influential in two scholarly organizations, the Association for Asian Studies' Committee on Chinese Thought (CCT) and the Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization (CSCC) of the American Council of Learned Societies. From 1950 on, Wright worked actively in the CCT, editing its journal, serving on its board, and from 1963-1965 working as its vice-president and president. From 1964-1973 he chaired the CSCC, working to organize conferences and develop sources of funding for scholarly endeavors in the field of pre-modern China.
After the death of his first wife, Wright married Marya Wankowicz Welch. They were living in Guilford, Connecticut, at the time of Wright's sudden death on August 11, 1976. From his first marriage Wright had two sons, Charles Duncan and Jonathan Arthur Wright.
MARY CLABAUGH WRIGHT, 1917-1970
Mary Clabaugh Wright was born on September 25, 1917, in Tuscaloosa, Alabama, the second child of Samuel Francis and Mary Bacon Clabaugh. She graduated from Vassar College in 1938 and began postgraduate studies in history at Radcliffe College, from where she received an A.M. in 1939. She became interested in the history of China, particularly the field of modern China. It was at this time that she met Arthur Wright, another graduate student, who was pursuing studies at Harvard in Chinese and Japanese.
Mary and Arthur Wright were married in Washington, D.C., on July 6, 1940, and then left the United States to carry on doctoral research in Japan and China. During 1940-1941, they lived in Kyoto and then moved to Peking in June 1941. After December 1941, the Wrights were stranded in China, and in March 1943, they were interned in a camp for enemy aliens at Wei-hsien, Shantung, where they remained until evacuated in October 1945.
The Wrights chose to remain in Peking to continue their studies. When the Hoover Library began a program to collect contemporary materials on the Chinese revolution, the Wrights became their China representatives. They travelled widely in China and met with Mao Tse-tung. Mary Wright had great success in finding materials and she became an expert on contemporary Chinese materials. The collection program became essentially hers, and when in 1947 the Wrights returned to the United States and Arthur Wright accepted an appointment in the history department at Stanford, Mary Wright became China curator at the Hoover Library.
Mary Wright received her Ph.D. from Radcliffe in 1951. Her dissertation, The Last Stand of Chinese Conservatism: The T'ungchih Restoration, 1862-1874, was published in 1957. The book was a model for the study of modern China and marked her as a major historian. Wright held faculty rank at the Hoover Library; though she lectured at Stanford she was not a member of the history faculty there.
In 1959 Arthur and Mary Wright were invited to join the history department at Yale University. Mary Wright came to Yale as an associate professor, the first tenured woman in the faculty of arts and sciences. Her scholarly interests now moved to the study of the processes of revolution. In 1965 she presided over a research conference on the Chinese revolution of 1911, which resulted in the publication of China in Revolution: The First Phase, 1900-1913, to which Wright contributed the introduction "The Rising Tide of Change." She helped found the society for Ch'ing Studies and its journal Ch'ing-shihwen-t'i. She also served on the Joint Committee on Contemporary China.
Mary Wright died in Guilford, Connecticut, on June 18, 1970. She was survived by her husband and two sons, Charles Duncan Wright (b. May 9, 1950) and Jonathan Arthur Wright (b. January 9, 1952).
Scope and Contents
The Arthur Frederick and Mary Clabaugh Wright Papers consist of correspondence, subject files, writings, research notes, and teaching materials which document Arthur Wright's career as a teacher and scholar of Chinese history. The papers also include personal letters to the Wright and Clabaugh families. The papers contain few documents relating to Mary Wright's scholarly career.
The bulk of the papers are professional files from Arthur Wright's office at Yale or study in Guilford, Connecticut. Marya Wright gave this portion of her husband's papers to the Yale University Library between 1978 and 1981. In 1981, Jonathan Wright supplemented this gift with a contribution of his parents' letters to their families from 1934-1947. John King Fairbank gave an additional gift of photocopies of Arthur and Mary Wright's correspondence with several friends and colleagues in 1982.
Though the papers contain materials from the 1930s through 1977, the bulk of the papers dates from after 1959, when the Wrights moved to Yale. The papers are arranged in two series and two additions:
I. CORRESPONDENCE AND TOPICAL FILES
II. COURSE AND RESEARCH FILES
Series I includes all correspondence, as well as organizational records of committees and research and publication projects in which Arthur Wright took an interest. The serles includes files for the Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization of the American council of Learned Societies, the Committee on Chinese Thought of the Association for Asian Studies, the Cambridge history of China, the history of man project, Sung project, and the Yale Faculty Seminar on Chinese and Comparative Historiography, as well as for Wright's own books and other writings. There are also files for professional colleagues such as Denis Twitchett, Frederick Mote, Herbert Franke, John Fairbank, Etienne Balazas, and Thomas C. Smith. With the latter Wright discussed personal matters such as his feelings about moving to New Haven, as well as more scholarly topics.
Other files include correspondence, writings, project outlines, and notes from students, publishers, journals, and educational associations and institutions. The most voluminous files are those for students such as Michael Freeman, Don Gillin, Conrad Schirokauer, Kent Clarke Smith, and Howard Wechsler, which include advise on research, manuscripts for papers, critiques of writings, and recommendations for fellowships and teaching positions. The file People's Republic of China trip contains Arthur Wright's journal and photographs from his 1973 visit to China. Correspondence with Owen Lattimore reveals the Wrights' support for a friend and colleague during his investigation by the House Un-American Activities Committee, while the file for Ch'ing-ling Sung (Madame Sun Yat-sen) shows the efforts Mary Wright made to help Madame Sun locate materials in the Hoover Collection.
The series also includes letters written by the Wrights to their respective families. In them Arthur Wright describes his studies at Stanford, Oxford, and Harvard and his courtship of Mary Clabaugh. Letters to the Clabaugh family include Mary Wright's depictions of the couple's early married life, their travels and studies in Japan and China, and their internment during World War II.
Files in this series are arranged in alphabetical order by personal, corporate, or project name. Within the file material is arranged in rough chronological order. No attempt has been made to cross-reference material found in a project folder to additional material of the same individual in a personal name folder. The files arranged under Arthur Wright's name include manuscript and printed copies of his writings and popular lectures as well as biographical information and memorial tributes.
Series II consists of notes, outlines, lists, student papers, printed material, clippings, illustrations, and maps collected by Arthur Wright in connection with his teaching and research. Material relating to Wright's courses, both undergraduate and graduate level at Stanford and Yale, is arranged at the beginning of the series by course title. It includes syllabi, lecture notes, and exam questions. The series concludes with boxes of research material arranged by topic, including card files of note cards. The topics are general headings reflecting Arthur Wright's interests in Chinese biography, religion, historiography, dynasties, and cities. within files there is little if any arrangement of material.
Asia; China -- Description and travel; China -- History -- Study and teaching; East Asia -- Study and teaching; Japan -- Description and travel; Wei Xian (Shandong Sheng, China); Educators; Historians; Balazas, Etienne; Fairbank, John King, 1907-1991; Franke, Herbert, 1914-2011; Gillin, Donald G.; Lattimore, Owen, 1900-1989; Mote, Frederick W., 1922-2005; Schirokauer, Conrad; Smith, Thomas C. (Thomas Carlyle), 1916-2004; Song, Qingling, 1893-1981; Twitchett, Denis Crispin, 1925-2006; Wechsler, Howard J.; Wright, Arthur F., 1913-1976; Wright, Mary Clabaugh, 1917-; American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization; Association for Asian Studies; Harvard University ( Students); Stanford University -- Faculty; University of Oxford -- Students; Yale University -- Faculty
- Correspondence and Topical Files, 1932-1977; Series I; 9.5
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in alphabetical order by personal, corporate, or project name. Within the file material is arranged in rough chronological order.
  - A, 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1960, 1973, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Academy of Arts and Science, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization, 1972 February-August (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization, 1972 September-December (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization, 1973 January-June (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization: Chin Dynastic History Project, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization: Ming Biographical History Project, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Council of Learned societies. Committee on studies of Chinese Civilization: minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization: Sung volume, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization. Subcommittee on Literature, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization. Subcommittee on the Ming-Ching continuum, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on studies of Chinese Civilization. Subcommittee on Art, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization. Subcommittee on Chinese Thought, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization: Taoism Conference, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Committee on Chinese Thought, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Committee on Chinese Thought, 1957 December (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Committee on Chinese Thought, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Committee on Chinese Thought, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Committee on Chinese Thought: rapporteur's report of the fifth conference, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Committee on Chinese Thought: Chinese thought volumes, 1953-1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Committee on Chinese Thought: Chinese thought volumes, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Committee on Chinese Thought: Chinese thought volumes, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Committee on Chinese Thought: Chinese thought volumes, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - B, 1949-1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - B, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - B, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - B, 1969-1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Balazas, Etienne, 1952-1957 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - See also: Sung project (Box 3)
  - Balazas, Etienne, 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    General note
    See also: Sung project
  - Balazas, Etienne, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Balazas Collectanea, 1963-1964, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Banno, Masataka, 1951-1972 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Bear, Peter, 1969-1975 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Bell, J. G., 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Bell, J. G., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Bell, J. G., 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Bell, J. G., 1965-1972 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Bibliographie Bouddhigue, 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Buddhism in Chinese History, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Buddhism in Chinese History, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Buddhism in Chinese History, 1965-1973 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - C, 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - C, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - C, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Cambridge History of China, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Cambridge History of China, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Cambridge History of China, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Cambridge History of China, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Cambridge History of China, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Chinese nationals at Yale, 1854-1954 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Chinese studies reports, 1952-1967 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - City in Late Imperial China, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - City in Late Imperial China, 1969-1976 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Clabaugh family, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Clabaugh family, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Clabaugh family, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Clabaugh family, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Clabaugh family, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Clabaugh family, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Clabaugh family, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Clabaugh family, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Communications and Propaganda in World History, 1969-1976 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Communications and Propaganda in World History, undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Communications and Propaganda in World History, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - D, 1968-1976 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - D. C. Heath, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - deBary, Theodore, 1960-1976 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Demieville, Paul, 1952-1971 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - DesForges, Roger, 1967-1975 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - E, 1960-1973, undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Eberhard, Wolfram, 1949-1963 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Encyclopaedia of World Biography, 1966-1970 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - F, 1947-1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Fairbank, John K.: Arthur Wright's file, 1950-1958 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Fairbank, John K.: Arthur Wright's file, 1960-1976 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Fairbank, John K.: Mary Wright's file, 1946-1959 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Fairbank, John K.: Mary Wright's file, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Fairbank, John K.: Mary Wright's file, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Fairbank, John K.: Mary Wright's file, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Fairbank, John K.: Mary Wright's file, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Farmer, Edward L., 1960-1975 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Franke, Herbert, 1954-1963 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Franke, Herbert, 1964-1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Freeman, Michael, 1968-1971 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Freeman, Michael, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Freeman, Michael, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Fujieda, Akira, 1963-1971 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - G, 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - G, 1962-1976 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Gillin, Don, 1954-1958 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Gillin, Don, 1959-1967 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Griswold, A. Whitney, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Grootaers, Willem A., 1951-1967 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - H, 1938, 1954-1961 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - H, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - H, 1965-1969 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - H, 1970-1976 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Harvard Journal of Asiatic Studies, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - History of Man project, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - History of Man project, 1972-1976 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Hsieh, Andrew, 1970-1975 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Huang, Ray, 1972-1976 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - I, 1965-1976 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - J, 1960-1975 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Journal of Asian Studies, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Journal of Chinese Philosophy, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Journal of the History of Ideas, 1959-1976 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - K, 1959-1964 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - K, 1966-1975 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Kapp, Robert, 1967-1972 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Kracke, Edward, 1959, 1967-1972, undated (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - L, 1948, 1959-1965 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - L, 1966-1970 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - L, 1971-1976 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Lattimore, David, 1961-1970 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1950-1966 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Lee, James, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Lee, James, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - Levenson, Joseph R., 1950-1977 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - Liu, James T. c., 1959-1971, undated (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Loehr, Max, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Loehr, Max, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Loehr, Max, 1951-1960 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - M, 1949-1960 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - M, 1961-1965 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - M, 1966-1969 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - M, 1970-1976 (Box 10, Folder 131)
  - Millinger, James, 1964-1973 (Box 10, Folder 132)
  - Mote, Frederick, 1959-1971 (Box 10, Folder 133)
  - Mote, Frederick, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - Mote, Frederick, 1973-1975, undated (Box 10, Folder 135)
  - N, 1957-1976 (Box 10, Folder 136)
  - Nakamura, Hajime, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 137)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Nivison, David, 1950-1965 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - O, 1960-1962 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Owen, Stephen, 1972, undated (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Oxnam, Robert, 1964-1974 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - P, 1960-1976 (Box 11, Folder 145)
  - Peasant, 1954-1956 (Box 11, Folder 146)
  - People's Republic of China trip, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 147)
  - People's Republic of China trip, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 148)
  - Perry, John curtis, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 149)
  - Picken, Laurence E. R., 1972-1975 (Box 11, Folder 150)
  - Powell, John Walker, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - R, 1959-1975 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Revue Bibliographie de Sinologie, 1957-1967 (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Rosenbaum, Arthur, 1962-1971 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - S, 1959-1965 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - S, 1966-1969 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - S, 1970-1976 (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Samson, Sir George, 1952-1959 (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Saso, Michael, 1965-1975 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Schirokauer, Conrad, 1950-1958 (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Schirokauer, Conrad, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - Schirokauer, Conrad, 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 162)
  - Schirokauer, Conrad, 1962-1976 (Box 13, Folder 163)
  - Selden, Mark, 1961-1965 (Box 13, Folder 164)
  - Selden, Mark, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Seymour professorship, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Shakabpa, Tsepan, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Sickman, Laurence, 1966, 1974-1976 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Skinner, G. William, 1966-1976 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Smith, Bardwell L., 1964-1975 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Smith, Jeanne and Thomas C., 1952-1959 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Smith, Jeanne and Thomas C., 1960 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Smith, Jeanne and Thomas C., 1961-1971, undated (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Smith, Kent Clarke, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Smith, Kent Clarke, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Smith, Kent Clarke, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Smith, Kent Clarke, 1966-1970 (Box 14, Folder 177)
  - Somers, Robert, 1970, undated (Box 14, Folder 178)
  - Speidel, William M., 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 179)
  - Spediel, William M., 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 180)
  - Speidel, William M., 1971-1975 (Box 14, Folder 181)
  - Stanford University Press
    See: Bell, J. G.
  - Strickmann, Michel, 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 182)
  - Sui volume, 1974, undated (Box 14, Folder 183)
    See also: Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.
  - Sung, Ch'ing-ling (Madame Sun Yat-Sen), 1949-1951, undated (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - Sung project, 1954-1957 (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - Sung project, 1960-1961 (Box 14, Folder 186)
  - Sung project, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 187)
  - Sung project, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 188)
  - Sung project, 1967-1969 (Box 14, Folder 189)